hi coach bre and terce here this is
going to be a quick video that reviews
The Long lever posterior tilt plank so
all I'm going to do I'm going to get in
a standard plank position with two
primary changes the first change is that
I'm going to narrow and lengthen the
base of support I'm going to do this by
instead of keeping my elbows directly
under my shoulders I'm going to put them
closer together and about 6 in apart and
then line my elbows up underneath my
nose rather than directly underneath my
shoulders that alone makes the exercise
more difficult but I'm also going to
engage in a posterior pelvic tilt and
the posterior pelvic tilt is achieved by
squeezing the glutes as hard as possible
and we when you do that when you squeeze
the glutes you are drawing your pelvic
bone up towards your head and your
tailbone down towards your feet so your
pelvis actually tilts rearward and you
were going to hold that so this is what
it looks
like I'm going to start in the prone
position rather than have my elbows
directly underneath my shoulders I'm
going to extend them out so they're
underneath my nose and I'm going to
narrow the base so where my elbows are
about 6 in
apart now I'm going to get in standard
plank position and then I'm going to
squeeze my glutes as as hard as possible
so come up to a plank squeeze my
glutes and then I'm going to hold that
position for approximately 30
seconds hope you enjoy the video